<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
The ASF licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in
compliance with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<document item-group="about">
    <properties>
        <title>About</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="What is Apache Pivot?">
            <p>
                Apache Pivot is an open-source platform for building rich internet applications in
                Java. It combines the enhanced productivity and usability features of a modern RIA
                toolkit with the robustness of the Java platform. Pivot applications are written
                using a combination of Java and XML and can be run either as an applet or as a
                standalone, optionally offline, desktop application.
            </p>
            <p>
                Like other modern development platforms, Pivot provides a comprehensive set of
                foundation classes that together comprise a "framework". These classes form the
                building blocks upon which more complex and sophisticated applications can be built.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Who is Pivot's target audience?">
            <p>
                Pivot was designed to be familiar to web developers who have experience building
                AJAX applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. However, it provides a much
                richer set of standard widgets than HTML, and allows developers to create
                sophisticated user experiences much more quickly and easily. Pivot will also seem
                familiar to Swing developers, as both Swing and Pivot are based on Java2D and
                employ a model-view-controller (MVC) architecture to separate component data from
                presentation. However, Pivot includes additional features that make building modern
                GUI applications much easier, including declarative UI, data binding, effects and
                transitions, and web services integration.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Pivot's History">
            <p>
                Pivot began as an R&amp;D effort at VMware in 2007 and was released as an
                open-source project in June 2008 under the Apache 2.0 license. Pivot joined the
                Apache Incubator in January 2009 and graduated as a top-level Apache project in
                December 2009. It is currently driven entirely by the software development
                community.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
