<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
The ASF licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in
compliance with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<document>
    <properties>
        <home>true</home>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <div id="stage">
            <p>
                Apache Pivot is an open-source platform for building rich Internet applications in
                Java. It combines the enhanced productivity and usability features of a modern RIA
                toolkit with the robustness of the Java platform.
            </p>

            <ul class="stageBtn">
                <li class="stageDemos">
                    <a href="demos/">
                        <strong>Demos</strong>
                        <em>What you can do with Pivot</em>
                    </a>
                </li>
                <li class="stageDl">
                    <a href="download.cgi#{$version}">
                        <strong>Download</strong>
                        <em>The current release (<version/>)</em>
                    </a>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </div>

        <div id="featured" class="group">
            <div class="homeCol1">
                <h2>Why Pivot?</h2>
                <p>
                    Pivot is the only RIA framework that enables developers to build applications
                    for the Java platform using Java or any other JVM language, such as
                    JavaScript, Groovy, or Scala. Pivot is also the only truly open RIA framework:
                    it is completely open source, and is driven entirely by the software
                    development community.<br/><br/>
                </p>

                <p>
                    Pivot allows developers to work with the tools and APIs they already know,
                    reducing technology sprawl and streamlining solution technology stacks.
                </p>
                <!-- <div class="btnMore"><a href="about.html"><span>More about Pivot</span></a></div> -->
            </div>

            <div class="homeCol2">
                <h2>User Comments</h2>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <p>"We chose Pivot due to how rapidly we were able to create a user interface
                        and tie it into our existing API for our storage system. Pivot's straight-forward
                        collection model saved us the hassle of writing mountains of boilerplate code to
                        update the UI whenever low-level application state changed."</p>
                        <cite class="homeCol2">- Mike Smorul, University of Maryland Institute for Advanced Computer Study</cite>
                    </li>

                    <li>
                        <p>"I AM IMPRESSED. Web services, [data] binding, event handling, scripting in the UI
                        definition (in any JVM language)...and yes, a good-looking mechanism for static
                        localization. Keep going Apache Pivot - you are heading in the right direction!"</p>
                        <cite class="homeCol2">- Christophe Hanlon, ADINS sprl</cite>
                    </li>

                    <li>
                        <p>"From the perspective of someone who is fairly new to Pivot and writing a
                        decent-sized standalone app with it, I can say that Pivot's API is about
                        10,000 times cleaner than the other choices available for Java...If you need
                        to give a Java app a nice UI with little fuss, I recommend Pivot wholeheartedly."</p>
                        <cite class="homeCol2">- Clint Gilbert, Java developer</cite>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <!-- <div class="btnDocs"><a href="user-comments.html"><span>More user comments</span></a></div> -->
            </div>

            <div class="homeCol3">
                <h2>Latest Updates</h2>
                <ul class="newsItems">
                    <li>
                        <a href="download.cgi#{$version}">
                            <strong>Pivot 2.0 Released</strong>
                            <em>January 10, 2011</em>
                            <p>The latest version of Pivot is now available for download.</p>
                        </a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <!-- <div class="btnNewsArchive"><a href="news.html"><span>News archive</span></a></div> -->
            </div>
        </div>
    </body>
</document>
