<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Home</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Apache Pivot">

      <p>
        Pivot is a platform for building rich internet
        applications in Java. It combines the enhanced productivity and
        usability features of a modern RIA toolkit with the robustness
        of the industry-standard Java platform.
      </p>

      <p>
        <img src="./img/kitchen_sink.png" alt="Sample Pivot application" border="0" />
        <br/>
        <font color="#000000" size="-1" face="arial,helvetica,sanserif">
          <i>A sample Pivot application</i>
        </font>
      </p>

      <p>
        Pivot applications are written using a combination of Java and
        XML and can be run either as an applet or as a standalone
        (optionally offline) desktop application. While Pivot was designed
        to be familiar to web developers who have experience building AJAX
        applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, it provides a much
        richer set of standard widgets than HTML, and allows developers to
        create sophisticated user experiences much more quickly and easily.
        Pivot will also seem familiar to Swing developers, as both Swing and
        Pivot are based on Java2D and employ a model-view-controller (MVC)
        architecture to separate component data from presentation. However,
        Pivot includes additional features that make building modern GUI
        applications much easier, including declarative UI, data binding,
        effects and transitions, and web services integration.
      </p>

      <p>
        Apache Pivot is developed in an open and participatory environment and
        released under the <a href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/">Apache
        Software License</a>.  Apache Pivot is intended to be a collaboration of the
        best-of-breed developers from around the world.  We invite you to
        participate in this open development project.  To learn more about getting
        involved, <a href="./get-involved.html">click here</a>.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section name="News">
      <p>
        <i>12/16/2009</i> Pivot has graduated! We are currently putting the finishing
        touches on our new site design and forthcoming 1.4 release, and will soon be 
        moving to our new home at 
        <a href="http://pivot.apache.org/">http://pivot.apache.org/</a>. Our mailing 
        lists and Subversion repository will also be moving; check here for updates over
        the next few weeks.
      </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
